<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mehul Kothari on Mehul Kothari</title>
    <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mehul Kothari on Mehul Kothari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>News Popularity Prediction With Ensemble Methods Of Classification</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/publication/monitor-eye-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/publication/monitor-eye-care/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Library</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/local-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/local-library/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Eye-Care System using Blink Detection A Convolutional Neural Net Approach</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/publication/news-popularity-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/publication/news-popularity-prediction/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cric-Bot</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/cric-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/cric-bot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed a cognitive document search for the cricket rules using the Microsoft Cognitive Services.
Generated keywords for document search, using the Language Understanding Intelligent Service(LUIS).
Designed an API in Django Python which analyzed the keywords obtained from LUIS and generated a response on the basis of different intent scores.
Scraped the International Cricket Rules website using Python Scrapy framework for creating a local database of rules.
Designed an Android app and a website for enhanced user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fake-net</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/fake-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/fake-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed an application which aims at classifying fake news, summarizes news articles from various sources and determined the probability of credibility of news articles using machine learning.
Generated headline for summarized news articles.
Implemented assignment of credibility scores to news articles.
Collected news articles from various sources using a web crawler, Webhose.
Extracted keywords and summarized individual news articles using Google&amp;rsquo;s PageRank Algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goverment Portal</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/government-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/government-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed and developed a public forum using Django Python web framework which allowed citizens of the state to post their problems which are either locality specific or general problems.
Developed a real-time notification system using the python package SwampDragon along with Redis server and inculcated live news feed using the News API.
Implemented the complexity of different models including likes, comments and notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Management System</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/project-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/project-management-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed a Java application to ease the process of project evaluation by letting college students form groups and upload projects and teachers to grade projects.
Analyzed and implemented a one-time login system by issuing a HTTP request to whatismyip.com and used mysql server to maintain the records.
Designed the user interface using JavaFx API along with Scene Builder 2.0.
Integrated and configured ftpserver to store the uploaded projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spon-taneous</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/spon-taneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/spon-taneous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed an Android app which gave companies and students a common platform to interact regarding sponsorship for college fests and events.
Integrated Firebase for real time database server and authentication system.
Implemented functionalities like notification system using the Notification Manager, real time chat server using FireBase and an alert system using Android Services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlas</title>
      <link>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mehul-kothari.github.io/project/atlas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
